Andrew Keith Davisson

(843) 696-5130 | akdavisson4@amail.com | Github | LinkedIn

Profile

Full stack web developer with experience in Javascript, Ruby, Rails, and React. Changing career paths after 5 years of experience as a Systems Administrator managing Windows and Linux servers on various hypervisors and networks. Additional experience with Ansible and Amazon Web Services. Strong desire to make things simple and efficient.

Technical Projects

Wacky Stories Github | Demo

This application mimics Mad Libs. A user is presented with types of words to come up with and is then presented with a story where those words are used.

- Uses Rails to build an API that provides endpoints for the story templates and solutions
- Frontend is built using React and bootstrap for minimal styling
- Uses Redux to keep templates and solutions in a state for the whole application to reference

Meme Generator Github | Demo

This application allows users to build memes by choosing from a selection of images and creating phrases to go along with the image.

- A Rails API is utilized to provide endpoints for images, phrases, and saved memes
- Application is a single page and JavaScript is used to manipulate the DOM

Rails Project Library Github | Demo

This application mimics a library where 'librarians' can add genres, authors, and books, and users can check in/out books.

- Full project is built using Ruby on Rails with minimal styling using bootstrap
- Utilizes bcrypt for password encrypting
- Allows authentication using Google accounts

Technical Skills

Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React/Redux, Ansible, Docker, Powershell, Amazon WebServices, HTML/CSS

Work Experience

Incident Response Analyst II - Flexential

April 2019 - May 2019

Aurora, CO

- Responsible for troubleshooting 100+ networks and client environments.
- Manage Windows and Linux servers.
- ▶ Manage Cisco, Fortigate, and Juniper networking equipment.
- Manage and troubleshoot multiple VMWare environments.

Systems Administrator - Flagship Biosciences Inc.

June 2017 - January 2019

Westminster, CO

- Deploy and maintain Windows and Linux servers utilizing XenServer hypervisor.
- Automate configuration and maintenance of Linux HPC cluster using Ansible
- ► Setup and deploy Ubuntu Linux desktops through Citrix XenDesktop.
- Manage and monitor daily data backups to AWS S3 storage using CloudBerry Backup.

Systems Administrator - RPWB, LLC.

July 2014 - June 2017

Mount Pleasant. SC

- Deploy and manage servers using VMWare.
- Complete small programming and scripting projects using C#, .NET, and Powershell.
- Manage various user administration tasks including Active Directory and Exchange.
- Manage and Monitor backups to disk and tape using Backup Exec.

Education

Certifications

B.S. Computer Information Systems Clemson University Clemson, SC May 2014 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Valid thru 2/28/2020

Full-Stack Web Development Flatiron School November 2019 AWS Certified Developer - Associate Valid thru 8/3/2020

> CompTIA Security+ Valid thru 3/12/2021

ITIL Foundations v4